NUR MUHAMMAD HASSAN

MOBILE APP & WEBSITE DEVELOPER

CONTACT 08063466463, 09076191943 nurmuhass@gmail.com 17b Tai Solarin Avenue Gwarinpa, Abuja Nurmuhass.vercel.app SKILLS Node Js PHP Next Js MYSOL HTML &CSS Jquery **JAVASCRIPT** Ajax React Native Firebase React Js C++ EDUCATION Bachelor of Science (B.SC) in **Computer Science Federal University of Maiduguri** (Unimaid) 2017-2023 **National Diploma National Diploma In Electrical And Electronics Engineering** 2016 - 2018Senior Secondary Certificate (SSCE) **El-Kanemi Collegeof Islamic** Theology, Maiduguri 2010 - 2016LANGUAGES English = Arabic Hausa

Kanuri

PROFILE

A web and Mobile App developer with a passion for creating fullstack beautiful, functional, and user-centered digital experiences. With 6 years of experience in the field. I am always looking for new and innovative ways to bring my clients visions to life.

I am capable of working on all aspects of web and mobile development, from clients side interfaces to server-side logic.

Whether I am working on a website, mobile app, or other digital product, I bring my commitment to design excellence and user-centered thinking to every project I work on. I look forward to the opportunity to bring my skills and passion to your next project.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer: Web developer and Mobile App Developer Ja

January 2019 - Present

- Proficient in both front-end and back-end development.
- Creating visually appealing layouts and user interfaces.
- Integrating APIs and backend services for data retrieval and storage.
- Providing consultancy and guidance on the best technologies and approaches for the project.
- Creating custom web and mobile solutions tailored to clients' specific needs and requirements.
- Collaborating with clients to understand their goals and deliver highquality solutions.
- Designing and implementing database structures using technologies like MySQL, MongoDB, or Firebase.
- Integrating native modules and components to access device-specific functionalities.
- Integrating native modules and components to access device-specific functionalities.
- Building e-commerce websites and mobile apps with features such as product catalogs, shopping carts, and payment gateways.
- Ensuring app responsiveness and optimal performance on iOS and Android platforms

Police Health Maintenance Limited (PHML),

June 2023 – Present

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop custom applications to meet specific business needs.
- Led the successful deployment of Register Conversion Application.
- Provided efficient IT support to end-users, resolving hardware and software issues promptly.
- Managed and maintained the organization's IT infrastructure, ensuring seamless operations.
- Implemented proactive measures that led to a 30% reduction in system downtime.
- Administered and optimized application performance, ensuring a smooth user experience.

Federal University of Maiduguri (Unimaid)

March 2022 - January 2023

- Implementing responsive and user-friendly interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Ensuring cross-browser compatibility and optimizing website performance.
- Collaborating with designers to translate wireframes and mockups into code.
- Building server-side logic and database management using programming languages like PHP, Firebase or Mongo db.
- · Implementing security measures and handling data encryption.
- Working on all aspects of web development, from client-side interfaces to server-side logic.
- Ensuring a consistent and cohesive design throughout the website.
- Planning, organizing, and coordinating web development projects.
- Implementing security measures to protect websites from vulnerabilities and attacks.

Power Holding Company Nigeria (PHCN)

May 2017- October 2017

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners.
- Testing new technology
- Implemented and administered technical solutions.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks.

Independent National Electoral Commission(INEC)

Febuary 2019- April 2019

- In charge of all activities at the polling unit on Election Day including polling, sorting and counting of votes as well as announcement of election result(s).
- Takes delivery and inspection of all materials and equipment for election from the supervisory presiding officer and ensures their security, particularly the sensitive materials, such as ballot papers and result forms; \(\mathbb{O} \) Coordinate activities in the voting points under his supervision.
- · Conducting of voter education ahead of polling.
- Returning of all election materials, other than the result sheet and card reader, to the SPO for delivery to EO after elections

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATION

- · Excellent human relation skills
- · Ability to work with little or no supervision
- · Good communication skills
- Professional, good organization capacity, motivated, open, creative, mature, responsible, flexible, and culturally sensitive

HOBBIES

- Travelling
- Reading
- Research

REFERENCES

Yamoram Alkali

HOD Department of English, Mohammed Goni College Maiduguri Borno State

Phone:08036002338

Email: Yamoramalkali@gmail.com

• MR ILOEABUNAM OKECHUKWU

Head Data Management & Analysis Unit Police Health Maintenance Limited Jabi, Abuja

Phone: 08036762061

Email: OKEYILOSON@YAHOO.COM

· Ibrahim Mahmoud

lecturer, department of sociology, Yobe state University

Phone: 08030632164

E-MAIL: alkaliibrahim59@gmail.com